Curriculum Vitae

Lisa Michelle Mhlongo Baker

3 December 2023

I'm Lisa Michelle Mhlongo Baker, a certified professional Digital Marketer (CDMP) with a burning passion for helping businesses thrive in the digital world. With over 3 years of experience, I specialise in digital marketing, content creation, branding, and business strategy.

Personal Information

Full name: Lisa Michelle Mhlongo Baker

Date of Birth: 21 February 1992

Gender: Female Citizenship: South Africa

Current occupation: Digital Brand Marketer

Contact number: +27 69 161 9804

Email: tlisamichelle@gmail.com

Languages: English, Zulu

Educational History

Secondary:	New Forest High School Matric certificate received	2005–2009 December 2009
Tertiary:	University of KwaZulu Natal (UKZN) BCom (Management & Economics) received	2010–2013 December 2013
	University of KwaZulu Natal (UKZN) BSocSci (Hons) (Economic History) received	2015–2016 December 2016
	IIE Vega Master of Commerce	2022–now in progress

Work Experience

Brand Manager

HyperionDev Cape Town (Hybrid) Feb 2023–present

- Owned visual style guides, copy guidelines, and restrictions, ensuring adherence to brand standards.
- Acted as the first line of defence and quality assurance in the team. Collaborate with internal and external stakeholders, especially higher education institutions' marketing teams.
- Supported Production/Operations within Marketing, ensuring quality control or quality assurance of branded collateral.
- Supported recruitment. Sourced, selected, and sold A Players to join the company.

Marketing Associate

HyperionDev Cape Town (Hybrid) Sep 2022–Feb 2023

- Developed a monthly plan for social content and email.
- Wrote all social copy, maintaining the brand tone and vibe.
- Collaborated with designers for all design requirements.
- Wrote & scheduled posts.
- Managed community.
- Created and maintained blog content.
- Ran social media promo campaigns: Black Friday & Price Increase.
- Managed mass email marketing for monthly promos.

Content Creator

Floww.io London (Remote) Mar 2022–Sep 2022

- Created content and wrote copy for B2B.
- Researched content ideas related to startups and markets.
- Collaborated with international content and data team members.

Intern

NT Communications Durban (Hybrid) Nov 2021-Feb 2022

- Contributed ideas and content for digital marketing campaigns for raising brand awareness
- Researched and developed themes, content ideas and captions for social media marketing.

Recruitment Lead & Market Researcher

Digify Africa Johannesburg (Remote) Jun 2021–Jul 2021 Oct 2020–Dec 2020

- Assisted Partnerships Manager with lead follow-up, meetings and database management.
- Sourced, advised and managed campaign marking collateral for website and social media from digital and design teams. Implemented lead generation process to meet weekly goals.

Skills

- Certified DMP
- Content Marketing
- Social Media Marketing
- SEO
- PPC (Google Ads)
- Display Advertising & YouTube
- Email Marketing
- Website Optimization
- Google Analytics
- Digital Marketing Strategy

Tech Stack Expertise

Marketing

- Sprout Social
- \bullet Hubspot
- Sendgrid
- Intercom
- Figma
- Canva
- Filmora

Operations

- Google Analytics
- Google Workspace
- Basecamp
- \bullet Asana
- Notion